Guide to the Sarah Wood Zine Collection, 1990s RL.01411
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sarah Wood Zine collection
1990s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Wood, Sarah, collector
RL.01411
2 Linear Feet
Sarah Wood was the co-owner of GERLL Press, a zine distro based in Chicago, Ill., in the early to mid-1990s. The collection consists of about 150 zines self-published by women and girls, largely in the United States. Subjects include feminism, the riot grrrl movement, body image and consciousness, women's health, women athletes, sexual abuse, television and film, poetry and short stories, rock music and punk music, violence against women, sexual identity, homosexuality, and bisexuality. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
150 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Sarah Wood Zine Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2003.
Biographical Note
Sarah Wood, along with her friend Kelly Curry, founded and owned GERLL (Girls Empowered Resisting Labels and Limits) Press, a zine distro based in Chicago, Ill., in the early to mid-1990s.
Collection Overview
The collection consists of about 150 zines self-published by women and girls, largely in the United States. Many of these zines come directly from the GERLL Press inventory, or were submitted to Wood and Curry by their authors to be considered for sale through the distro. Subjects include feminism, the riot grrrl movement, body image and consciousness, women's health, women athletes, sexual abuse, television and film, poetry and short stories, rock music and punk music, violence against women, sexual identity, homosexuality, and bisexuality. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Comic books, strips, etc.; Feminism -- United States; Women's periodicals, American; Women -- United States -- Social conditions; Women -- Health and hygiene -- United States; Women -- Psychology; Fan magazines; Women athletes -- United States; Women poets; Abused women; Homosexuality; Sexual orientation; Underground press publications -- United States; Periodicals -- Publishing -- United States; Women -- Comic books, strips, etc.; Self-publishing; Wood, Sarah, collector; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- 20 Bus (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  San Francisco, CA
- Action Girl Newsletter, no. 4 (Box 1)
  Staten Island, NY
- Another Lo-Fi Xtravaganza: Testimony #1: "Patrice", 1993 (Box 1)
  Olympia, WA
- April Fools' Day, no. 1 (Box 1)
- Bloody Knuckles Club (Box 1)
- Bust, vol. 1, July 1993 (Box 1)
  New York, NY
- Butterfly: A publication for women artists, no. 4, Summer 1995 (Box 1)
  Bellevue, WA
- Cake Walk: Let Them Eat Cake, April 1997 (Box 1)
  Boston, MA
- Cherub (Box 1)
  Reston, VA
- Colors of Corruption, no. 1 (Box 1)
  Syracuse, NY
- Completion of Circles (Box 1)
  Greenfield, WI
- Crème Brulee, no. 1, July 1993 (Box 1)
  Chicago, IL
- Cross My Heart (hope to die) (Box 1)
- Dead Jackie Susann Quarterly (Box 1)
- Design #816 (Box 1)
  Madison, WI
- Design #816, no. 8 (Box 1)
- Don't Dis Dolly, no. 1 (Box 1)
- Doris, no. 12 (Box 1)
  Asheville, NC
- Exile (Box 1)
  Los Angeles, CA
- Fantastic Fanzine, no. 4 (Box 1)
  Arlington, VA
- Feminism and the Revolt of Nature: Poetry is not a Luxury; Poems by Grace Paley and Mary Hope Lee (Box 1)
  Minneapolis, MN
- Femme Flicke, no. 5 (Box 1)
  Cambridge, MA
- Fern, no. 3 (Box 1)
  Berkeley, CA
- Fern, no. 4 (Box 1)
- Fern, no. 5 (Box 1)
- Fern, no. 6 (Box 1)
- Fern, no. 7 (Box 1)
- Fern, no. 8 (Box 1)
- Fern, no. 9 (Box 1)
- Fern, no. 10 (Box 1)
- Fern, no. 11 (Box 1)
- Five Strategies for the Unleashing of Girl Power (Box 1)
  United Kingdom
- Fix Me (Box 1)
- Function Zine, no. 11 (Box 1)
  Canosa Park, CA
- Function, no. 7 (Box 1)
  Newbury Park, CA
- Funkapotamus: Love, no. 4, 1992 (Box 1)
  St. Louis, MO
- Geek Girl, no. 2, May 1995 (Box 1)
  Lake Bluff, IL
- Get Off My Property (Box 2)
  Omaha, NE
- Girl Fiend, no. 7 (Box 2)
  Amherst, MA
- Girl Fiend, no. 8, 1995 (Box 2)
- Girl Wonder, no. 8 (Box 2)
  New Brunswick, NJ
- Girljock, no. 16, 1997 (Box 2)
- Grope, June 1994 (Box 2)
  Arcata, CA
- Growing Pains, no. 1 (Box 2)
- Gunk: Have you seen me? "What degenerate created this abortion?," no. 4 (Box 2)
  Basking Ridge, NJ
- Hamster Man, 1993 (Box 2)
  Bellwood, IL
- Hands Off (Box 2)
  Lake Zurich, IL
- Hands Off, part 2 (Box 2)
- Healing Stone (Box 2)
- How to Buy 2nd Hand Guitars and Amps: Without Getting Ripped Off (Box 2)
- Hunger Strike (Box 2)
  London, England
- I Am Intimate With Anger, no. 2 (Box 2)
  Goleta, CA
- I Know What You Did to Me (Box 2)
- I Love Me, no. 1 (Box 2)
- I'll Make a Deal With You: A whole bunch of VEGAN recipes, facts, and ideas, no. 1, Dec. 1993 (Box 2)
  Kirkland, WA
- I'm a Dimpled Lunatic (Just Like a Girl) (Box 2)
- I'm So Fucking Beautiful, no. 1 (Box 2)
- I'm So Fucking Beautiful, no. 2 (Box 2)
- I'm So Fucking Beautiful, no. 2.5 (Box 2)
- Impossible Schizoid Girl (Box 2)
  Portland, OR
- It's a Grrrl! (Box 2)
- It's a Grrrl!, no. 2 (Box 2)
- I've Got Angels in My Head (Box 2)
- Jigsaw, no. 1 (Box 2)
- Jigsaw, no. 2, Feb. 1990 (Box 2)
- Jigsaw, no. 3, 1991 (Box 2)
- Jigsaw, no. 4, Summer 1991 (Box 2)
- Jigsaw, no. 5 (Box 2)
- Jigsaw, no. 5.5 (Box 2)
- Jungle Gym: Zine distro machine, no. 3, Spring 1994 (Box 2)
  Washington, DC
- Just One Match: The Calling, no. 5 (Box 2)
  Rapid City, SD
- Lardass, no. 7, Nov. 1993 (Box 3)
  Gainesville, FL
- Lesbianism: An Act of Resistance: Uses of the Erotic: the Erotic as Power; Poetry by Marge Pierce (Box 3)
- Letters to Michelle (Box 3)
  Downers Grove, IL
- Libel, no. 15 (Box 3)
  Sarasota, FL
- Looking Straight Down (a selection of people and their thoughts on life), 1993? (Box 3)
  St. Charles, MO
- Love is Love isn't, no. 1 (Box 3)
  Manchester, MA
- Mad Planet, no. 3, 1993 (Box 3)
- Mama Girl, no. 1 (Box 3)
- Marika: bi: May & Erika (Box 3)
- Men Speaking Out on Men and Sexism, no. 2 (Box 3)
  Leeds, England
- Ms. America Zine, no. 3 (Box 3)
- Mudflap, no. 6 (Box 3)
- Music Master (Box 3)
  Milwaukee, WI
- Nerd Girl, no. 2 (Box 3)
  Seattle, WA
- Nerd Girl, no. 3 (Box 3)
- No Longer Silent!, no. 4/5 (Box 3)
  Tucson, AZ
- Oppression Song: A long needed reflection, no. 1 (Box 3)
  Ann Arbor, MI
- Pacifier (Box 3)
- Peach: Jill's Guide to TV & Movies (Box 3)
  Dakota Dunes, SD
- Pirate Radio: Kills the Ruling Class Stars (Box 3)
- Please Don't Hit Beneath the Belt! (Box 3)
- Power Candy, no. 1, June 1993 (Box 3)
  Kansas City, MO
- Queenie, no. 2 (Box 3)
- Queenie, no. 3 (Box 3)
- Rage Against, no. 2 (Box 3)
- Real: the zine for people who are, no. 1, 1994 (Box 3)
  Burlington, NC
- Rendezvous with Violence, no. 6.5, Aug. 1995 (Box 3)
  Brighton, MA
- Riot Gear, no. 3, March 1992 (Box 3)
- Riot Grrrl Eureka/Arcata (Box 3)
  Eureka, CA
- Riotemptresses, no. 1 (Box 3)
  Lexington, KY
- Rollerderby, no. 13 (Box 3)
  Guerneville, CA
- Rubyfruit Manifesto, no. 2, August 1998 (Box 3)
  Carrboro, NC
- Runt, no. 18, August 1993 (Box 3)
  Merion, PA
- Sacred Places (Box 3)
- Safety Pin, no. 2 (Box 3)
- Satanic Toasters, no. 7 (Box 3)
- Saturnine's Smile: An adventure zine with multiple choices (Box 3)
- Secret Weapon, no. 2 (Box 3)
- Septophilia Records (Box 4)
  Iowa City, IA
- Six Degrees of Separation (Box 4)
  Hartford, CT
- Sky Flying By, no. 5, June 1994 (Box 4)
  Murfreesboro, TN
- Smart Like Eve (Box 4)
- Sourpuss, no. 9 (Box 4)
  Pittsburgh, PA
- Sparkly Kitty Stickers, no. 3, 1993 (Box 4)
  Santa Rosa, CA
- Spirals Upward (Box 4)
- Splatterspleen, no. 4, June 1995 (Box 4)
  St. Paul, MN
- Square One, no. 3 (Box 4)
  Bronxville, NY
- Square One, no. 4 (Box 4)
- Stifled Fanzine, no. 5.7, August 1995 (Box 4)
  Woonsocket, RI
- Sweetarts Fanzine (Box 4)
  Lincoln, NE
- Taking No for An Answer, no. 2, December 1995 (Box 4)
- Taylor's Daughter, no. 2 (Box 4)
  Allston, MA
- There's a Boy in the Girl's Bathroom, no. 3 (Box 4)
  New Wilmington, PA
- Turtle Wax (Box 4)
  Chilton, WI
- Turtle Wax, no. 4 (Box 4)
- Two Weeks, August 1994 (Box 4)
- Under Control (Box 4)
- Untitled (Box 4)
  Lisle, IL
- Untitled (Box 4)
  Everett, WA
- Untitled, Oct. 1994 (Box 4)
- Untitled (Box 4)
- Untitled (Box 4)
- Up Yours, no. 1 (Box 4)
- Velvet Grass, no. 6, Summer 1995 (Box 4)
  Roanoke, VA
- Velvet Grass, no. 7 (Box 4)
- Weeds (Box 4)
- What is Riot Grrrl? (Box 4)
- What you can learn from a Glamour Girl (Box 4)
- Wives Tales (Box 4)
  San Diego, CA
- Women's Her-story, March 1995 (Box 4)
- Work: A zine 4 workin' women, no. 1 (Box 4)
- Written on a Body (Box 4)
- Yours Truly Comix: All About ME!, 1990 (Box 4)